Finding Aid for Provost and Executive Vice-President for Academic Affairs (University of Michigan) Supplemental Files, 1952-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Supplemental Files
  - Graduate Employees Organization (GEO) 1974-1977, 1.4 linear foot
    - Strike
      - Effects
        - Memos to Students Affected by Strike (Box 5)
        - Tuition Rebate, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Historical Files 1953-1974
    The Historical Files, 1953-1974 (0.5 lin. ft.) consist of material which predates the founding of the Office of Academic Affairs but includes subjects similar to those found in the Central Files subgroup. Material on the Netherlands Visiting Professorship, for example, dating from 1954 to 1962, is included in the historical file, whereas material on the same subject from later years can be found in the Central Files or Staff Files subgroups.
    - Appointment and Promotion Qualifications 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Awards 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    - Biological Sciences 1959-1960 (Box 5)
    - Botanical Gardens 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    - Calendar
      - Report of Commission on Year-Round Integrated Operation 1961 (Box 5)
      - Reports 1957-1958, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
    - Deanship Searches, Committee on 1968-1974 (Box 5)
    - Grievance Procedures 1960-1961 (Box 5)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of
      - Academic Counseling 1957-1958, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
      - Faculty Workload 1956-1957 (Box 5)
    - Netherlands Visiting Professorship 1954-1962, 7 folders (Box 5)
    - Phi Sigma Award Committee 1967/68-1973/74 (Box 5)
  - Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities (ISMRRD) 1963-1972
    The series Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities (ISMRRD) consists of 10 folders arranged chronologically spanning 1963 to 1972. ISMRRD was created in 1966 in response to a three-year study of the university's interests and goals in the study of mental retardation. Administratively, the institute came under the jurisdiction of the vice president for academic affairs until its closure in 1983.
    - 1963-1972, 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Management Advisory Group: Professional and Advisory Salary Implementation Program 1972-1973
    There is a small amount of material regarding the Management Advisory Group's Professional and Advisory Salary Implementation Program from 1972 and 1973.
    - General 1972-1973, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Appeals 1972-1973, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Residential College 1962-1967
    The Residential College series consists of eleven folders documenting the planning for and establishment of the Residential College in the early 1960s.
    - General 1962-1967, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Faculty Planning Committee 1961-1966, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Senate Advisory Committee on Staff Excellence 1959-1968
    The series Senate Advisory Committee on Staff Excellence, 1959-1968 (eight folders) includes reports and historical material relating to the activities of the committee.
    - General 1962-1968, 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Historical Materials 1959-1962 (Box 6)
    - Reports 1959-1968 (Box 6)
  - Awards 1982-1984
    The Awards series, 1982-1984 (2.3 lin. ft.), consists of nominations for various awards and honors by and on behalf of faculty and teaching assistants. Represented here are Achievement Awards, Amoco Teaching Awards, Distinguished University Professorships, Recognition Awards, and Teaching Assistant Awards nominations from 1982 to 1985. Due to the evaluative nature of the nominations, material in this series is restricted for thirty years from date of creation.
    - Achievement Awards Nominations
      - 1982/83-1983/84, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Amoco Teaching Awards Nominations
      - 1984-1985, 6 folders (Box 19)
    - Distinguished University Professorships Nominations
      - 1982 (Box 19)
      - 1983, 1985, 5 folders (Box 19)
    - Recognition Awards Nominations
      - 1982/83-1984/85, 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Teaching Assistant Awards Nominations
      - 1982/83-1983/84, 5 folders (Box 21)
  - Budget Priorities Committee (BPC) 1972-1989
    - General
      The Budget Priorities Committee (BPC) series, 1972-1989 (3 lin. ft.), includes historical information on the role and functions of the BPC and chronological files documenting the committee's retreats and reviews of university units from 1981/82 to 1991/92. Additional information on this committee can be found in the Central Files and the Staff Files subgroups.
      - Functions and Role of BPC 1972-1989 (Box 7)
      - Historical Information (Box 7)
      - Membership 1975-1992 (Box 7)
    - Chronological Files
      - 1972-1984, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - 1980/1981 (Box 7)
      - 1981/1982
        - Newsclippings (re: BPC Program Reviews), 2 folders (Box 7)
        - Program Review Charges (Box 7)
        - Retreat (Box 7)
        - Reviews
          - Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities (ISMRRD) (Box 7)
          - Plant Operations (includes 1987 memo) (Box 7)
      - 1982/1983
        - Newsclippings (re: BPC Program Reviews), 2 folders (Box 7)
        - Retreat (Box 7)
      - 1983/1984 (Box 7)
      - 1984/1985, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - 1985/1986, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - 1986/1987
        - General, 5 folders (Box 8)
        - Reviews
          - Michigan Media (Box 8)
          - Science and Technology, Institute of (Box 8)
        - Strategic Retreats/Budget Conferences (Box 8)
      - 1987/1988
        - General, 3 folders (Box 8)
        - Budget Recommendations (Box 8)
        - Strategic Retreat Summaries (Box 8)
      - 1988/1989
        - General, 7 folders (Box 8)
      - Strategic Retreat Summaries (Box 8)
      - 1989/1990
        - General, 6 folders (Box 9)
        - Strategic Retreat Summaries (Box 9)
      - 1990/1991, 5 folders (Box 9)
      - 1991/1992, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Higher Education General Information Survey (HEGIS) 1966-1973
    Material in the Higher Education General Information Survey (HEGIS) series, 1966-1973 (0.8 lin. ft.), consists of statistical and financial information supplied to the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare as part of the survey. Copies of the completed survey forms are contained in this series which includes information on enrollment, degrees awarded, faculty and staff, and budget.
    - Hegis Surveys 1966/67-1972/73, 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Proposals 1986-1987
    The Proposals series (2 lin. ft.) is divided into two subseries: Research Excellence Fund Proposals and Undergraduate Initiatives Fund Proposals, the latter comprising the bulk of the series. Materials include program and research proposals and reviewer comments from the academic year 1986/87.
    - Research Excellence Fund Proposals 1986/87 (Box 11)
    - Undergraduate Initiatives Fund Proposals 1986/87
      - Proposals #1-40 (Box 11)
      - Proposals #41-81 (Box 11)
      - Proposals #82-119 (Box 11)
      - Proposals #120-142 (Box 11)
      - Duderstadt, James, Comments of, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Reviewers' Comments, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Reports 1977-1993
    The Reports series, 1977-1993 (2 lin. ft.), is arranged alphabetically by title. With a few exceptions most of the reports date from the late 1980s and early 1990s and were prepared by various units on campus.
    - Admissions
      - Task Force on Undergraduate Admissions 1985-1986 (Box 13)
      - Undergraduate Admissions Advisory Committee 1987 (Box 13)
    - Bush Program in Child Development and Social Policy 1978-1984 (Box 13)
    - Capital Campaign Planning History 1977-1981, 2 volumes (Box 13)
    - Comprehensive Studies Program Mentorship 1988 (Box 13)
    - Computerized Academic Record 1990 (Box 13)
    - Development Study, (Grenzebach and Associates) 1979 (Box 13)
    - "Ebbs and Flows of Academic Reputation," 1993 (volume 1) (Box 13)
    - "Ebbs and Flows of Academic Reputation," 1993 (volume 2) (Box 14)
    - Expectations and Experiences of First Year Students with Diversity (The Michigan Study) 1993 (Box 14)
    - Functional Requirements for Financial Aid 1990 (Box 14)
    - Growth of the University, Plans Under Study 1964-1975 (Box 14)
    - Higher Education In Michigan (Briefing Book) 1992 (Box 14)
    - "The Meiland Report" Undergraduate Education in LS&A 1990 (Box 14)
    - Planning Committee on the Undergraduate Experience (PCUE) 1989-1990, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Retirement, Report of the Task Force on 1993 (Box 14)
    - Student Health Insurance Programmatic Review (Beckley and Associates) 1995 (Box 14)
    - University Hospital Briefing Book, ca. 1979 (Box 14)
    - Women's Issues: An Agenda for Action 1988-1990 (Box 14)
  - Reviews 1967-1996
    The Reviews series, 1967-1996 (3.6 lin. ft.), is arranged alphabetically by unit and covers a wide range of years beginning with the 1967 review of the Biological Station. Reviews with the most documentation are the 1982 review of the School of Art, and the 1993 Department of Population Planning and International Health review. The researcher should consult the boxlist for further information regarding units represented here
    The State Plan for Higher Education series, 1966-1968 (0.2 lin. ft.), documents the university administration's contributions to and comments on the State Plan for Higher Education developed by the State Board of Education in the mid 1960s, the purpose of which was to lay out the essential principles relating to planning and coordination of higher education in the state of Michigan. Also included here are files on the State Postsecondary Review Entity (SPRE), 1994-1995, from the 1990s in response to Higher Education Act Amendments of 1992.
    - Area Studies 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Art, School of 1982
      - D'Arms's (John) Summary Notebook (Box 15)
      - Letters from Various Sources re: Review (Box 15)
      - Notebook #1: Committee File, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Notebook #2: Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Notebook #3: Data and Informational Material, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Notebook #5: Letters from Committee, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Report of the Review Committee on the Master of Science Program in Medical and Biological Illustration 1980 (Box 15)
      - Statistics (Box 15)
      - Student Review 1981 (Box 15)
    - Biological Station at Douglas Lake 1967 (includes earlier printed materials), 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Department of Communication
      - Faculty Advisory Committee on the Department of Communication 1994 (Box 16)
      - Journalism Task Force 1994-1995 (Box 16)
      - "Journalism at Michigan" A Response to the Charge to the Faculty Advisory Committee on the Department of Communication," October 17, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Department of English Review 1992 (Box 16)
    - Department of Political Science Review 1993 (Box 16)
    - Developmental and Reproductive Biology, Consortium for Research in 1987 (appendices only) (Box 17)
    - Education, School of 1977
      - External Review Committee Report (Box 17)
      - Report of Committee to Evaluate the Combined Program in Education and Psychology 1976 (Box 17)
      - Some Background Data and Future Options for the School of Education (by Office of Academic Planning and Analysis) (Box 17)
    - Education, School of 1983
      - Physical Education, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Film and Video Studies Review 1993-1994 (Box 17)
    - Natural Resources, School of 1982, 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Public Health, School of, Department of Population Planning and International Health (PPIH) 1993
      - Background Materials
        - General (Box 18)
        - PPIH and Rackham Relationship (Box 18)
      - Budget Materials (Box 18)
      - Clippings (Box 18)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Box 18)
        - Letters of Concern (Box 18)
      - Discontinuance of Academic Programs (Box 18)
      - Electronic Mail (Box 18)
      - External Consultant (Box 18)
      - Faculty
        - General (Box 18)
        - Curriculum Vitae (Box 18)
        - Statistics (Box 18)
      - Possible Solutions (Box 18)
      - Public Forum Statements (Box 18)
      - Review Committee (Box 18)
      - Students (Box 18)
    - Social Research, Institute for 1986-1988 (Box 18)
  - State Plan for Higher Education (State Board of Education) 1966-1968
    - Study Steering and Advisory Committee 1966-1968, 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Provisional Plan 1968 (Box 18)
  - State Postsecondary Review Entities (SPRE) 1994-1995
    - General 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Dean and Director Reviews 1985-1998
    The Deans and Directors Reviews series, 1985-1997 (0.6 lin. ft.) contain information evaluating the job performance of deans and directors of schools, colleges and units. As personnel records, they are restricted for thirty years from the date of creation.
    - Art and Design, School of, Dean Review 1998 (Box 21)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2028 ]
    - Education, School of, Dean Review 1985 (Box 21)
    - Information, School of, Dean Review 1996 (Box 21)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2026 ]
    - Law, School of, Dean Review 1998 (Box 21)
    - Library, University, Director Review 1995 (Box 21)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2025 ]
    - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of, Dean Review (not reviewed) 1998 (Box 21)
    - Nursing, School of, Dean Review 1998 (Box 21)
    - Social Work, School of, Dean Review 1997 (Box 21)
      [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2027 ]
    - Associate Provost Review 1998 (Box 21)
  - Searches 1983-2001
    [PR RESTRICTED for 30 years from date of search]
    The Searches series, 1983-2001 (20 lin. ft.), contains the records from searches for deans, directors, and executive officers of various schools, colleges, and units, all of which are restricted for thirty years from date of creation. The series is arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the school or office. Within each unit, searches are arranged chronologically, with the successful candidate noted in parentheses.
    Search documents include:
    Advertising for the position
    Position description and selection criteria
    The search committee's charge, membership list, agendas and minutes, and its final report to the provost
    The provost's poll of the faculty regarding important characteristics of a new leader for the unit, report to the Regents and negotiations with finalists
    List of the candidates
    Finalists' files
    Timeline for the search
    Forms and form letters
    Interview questions and itineraries for campus visits; and
    Press and publicity regarding the search
    Additional search material may be found in the Central and Staff Files subgroups of the Provost and Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs records.
    - General
      - Search Procedures 1986-1997 (Box 22)
    - Admissions, Director of Undergraduate
      - 1987-1988 (Richard H. Shaw) (Box 22)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2018 ]
      - 1992-1993 (Theodore Spencer), 3 folders (Box 22)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2023 ]
    - Affirmative Action, Director of
      - 1988-1989 (Zaida I. Giraldo), 4 folders (Box 22)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2019 ]
    - Architecture and Urban Planning, School of
      - 1986 (Robert Beckley), 2 folders (Box 22)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2016 ]
      - 1996-1997 (Doug Kelbaugh)
        - Advertisement (Box 22)
        - Candidate Questions (Box 22)
        - Candidates (Box 22)
        - Final Report to the Provost (Box 22)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 22)
        - Provost Correspondence (Box 22)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 22)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 22)
        - Search Committee Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 22)
        - Search Consultants (Box 22)
        - Timeline (Box 22)
        - Women Candidates (Box 22)
        - Finalist Files, 5 folders (Box 22)
    - Art, Museum of
      - 1989 (William J. Hennessey)
        - Background Information on the Museum of Art (Box 23)
        - Candidate Evaluations (Box 23)
        - Candidates (Box 23)
        - Correspondence (Box 23)
        - Interview Questions (Box 23)
        - Issues (Box 23)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 23)
        - Finalist Files, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - 1997 (William J. Hennessey)
        - Advertisement (Box 23)
        - Affirmative Action (Box 23)
        - Background on the Museum (Box 23)
        - Boylan Report -- "Issues Relating to the Museum of Art" (Box 23)
        - Candidates (Box 23)
        - Correspondence (Box 23)
        - Final Report to the Provost (Box 23)
        - Forms and Form Letters (Box 23)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 23)
        - Search Consultants (Box 23)
        - Timeline (Box 23)
        - Finalist Files, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Art [and Design], School of
      - 1984-1985 (Marjorie Levy) (Box 23)
      - 1992-1993 (Allen Samuels)
        - Advertisement (Box 23)
        - Affirmative Action (Box 23)
        - Appointment of Allen Samuels (Box 23)
        - Candidates (Box 23)
        - Final Report to the Provost (Box 23)
        - Interview Questions (Box 23)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 23)
        - Provost's Correspondence (Box 23)
        - Provost's Poll of the Faculty on Key Issues for the School of Art (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 23)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 23)
        - Search Consultants (Box 23)
        - Transition (Box 23)
        - Timeline (Box 23)
        - Finalist Files, 5 folders (Box 23)
      - 1998-2000 (Bryan Rogers)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2030 ]
        - Advertisement (Box 23)
        - Background Information on the School of Art and Design (Box 23)
        - Campus Visits (Box 23)
        - Candidates (Box 23)
        - Final Report to the Provost (Box 23)
        - Interview Questions (Box 23)
        - Panel Discussion with School of Art and Design Alumni (Box 23)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 23)
        - References (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Agendas (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Meeting Minutes (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 24)
        - Search Consultants (Box 24)
        - Timeline (Box 24)
        - Finalist Files, 5 folders (Box 24)
        - 9 VHS videotapes of candidate presentations 1999 (Box 24)
    - Athletics, Direct of Intercollegiate
      - 1993 (M. Joseph Roberson) (Box 24)
    - Business Administration, School of
      - 1990-1991 (B. Joseph White)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2021 ]
        - Affirmative Action (Box 24)
        - Candidates (Box 24)
        - Feedback on Candidates (Box 24)
        - Forms and Form Letters (Box 24)
        - Press (Box 24)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 24)
        - Search Consultants (Box 24)
        - Timeline (Box 24)
        - Finalist Files, 6 folders (Box 24)
      - 2000-2001 (Robert Dolan)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2031 ]
        - Advertisement (Box 24)
        - Affirmative Action (Box 24)
        - Background information on the Business School (Box 24)
        - Candidates (Box 24)
        - Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Faculty Poll regarding search (Box 24)
        - Interviews--Campus Visit (Box 24)
        - Interviews--First Round (Box 24)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
        - Open forums (Box 24)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 24)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 25)
        - Search Consultants (Box 25)
        - Timeline (Box 25)
        - Finalist Files, 3 folders (Box 25)
        - Candidate Files, 35 folders (Box 25)
          [Retain until 2007]
    - Center for Afro-American and African Studies, Director of the
      - 1989-1991 (Earl Lewis) (Box 25)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching, Director of the
      - 1992-1993 (Constance Cook) (Box 25)
    - Counseling Services, Director of
      - 1990-1991 (A. Delories Sloan)
        - Other Candidates (Box 25)
        - Search Committee (Box 25)
        - Finalist File (Box 25)
    - Dentistry, School of
      - 1988-1989 (Bernard Machen)
        - Advertisement (Box 25)
        - Background Information on School of Dentistry including School of Dentistry Retreat, 2 folders (Box 25)
        - Candidates (Box 25)
        - Correspondence 1985-1993, 2 folders (Box 25)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 26)
        - Provost's Poll of the Faculty on Key Issues (Box 26)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 26)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 26)
        - Search Consultants (Box 26)
        - Finalist Files, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Education, School of
      - 1987-1988 (Cecil Miskel)
        - Candidate Evaluations/Rankings (Box 26)
        - Candidate Lists (Box 26)
        - Consultants (Box 26)
        - Issues (Box 26)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 26)
        - Search Committee General (Box 26)
        - Search Committee Meeting Notes (Box 26)
        - Search Committee Memos (Box 26)
        - Finalist Files, 5 folders (Box 26)
      - 1997-1998 (Not filled)
        - Advertisement (Box 26)
        - Candidates (Box 26)
        - Correspondence (Box 26)
        - E-mails (Box 26)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 26)
        - Press, Forums and Timelines (Box 26)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 26)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes, 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 26)
        - Search Consultants (Box 26)
        - Finalist Files, 4 folders (Box 26)
      - 1999 (Karen Wixon)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2029 ]
        - Wixon, Karen (Box 26)
    - Engineering, College of
      - 1986 (Charles Vest) (Box 26)
      - 1988-1990 (Dan Atkins, interim, Peter Banks)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2020 ]
        - Advertisement (Box 27)
        - Candidates (Box 27)
        - Correspondence (Box 27)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 27)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 27)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 27)
        - Search Consultants (Box 27)
        - Timelines and Flowcharts (Box 27)
        - Vice President for Academic Affairs Poll of the Faculty (Box 27)
        - Atkins, Dan (Box 27)
        - Banks, Peter (Box 27)
      - 1994-1995 (Stephen Director)
        - Advertisement (Box 27)
        - Background on the College of Engineering (Box 27)
        - Candidates (Box 27)
        - Correspondence (Box 27)
        - Final Report to the Provost (Box 27)
        - Forms and Form Letters (Box 27)
        - Interview Questions (Box 27)
        - Position Description and Selection Criteria (Box 27)
        - Press (Box 27)
        - Provost's Report to the Regents (Box 27)
        - Search Committee Agendas and Minutes (Box 27)
        - Search Committee Membership (Box 27)
        - Search Consultants (Box 27)
        - Timeline (Box 27)
        - Finalist Files, 4 folders (Box 27)
    - Executive Vice President for Medical Affairs
      - 1996-1997 (Gilbert S. Omenn)
        - General (Box 27)
        - Finalist Files, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Financial Aid, Director of the Office of
      - 1996-1997 (Pamela Fowler)
        - Advertisement (Box 27)